<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Gopi Palaniappan</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Gopi Palaniappan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://gopipm.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Classic Apple Catch Game</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/002-apple-catch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/002-apple-catch/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-fun-fast-paced-arcade-game">&lt;strong>A Fun, Fast-Paced Arcade Game&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3> &lt;p>Get ready for some classic arcade fun with &amp;ldquo;Apple Catch&amp;rdquo;! This charming game challenges your reflexes with a simple, addictive goal: move the basket at the bottom of the screen to catch the red apples as they fall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The controls are intuitive – just move your mouse left and right to guide the basket. Each apple you successfully catch adds to your score, which is proudly displayed in the top-left corner. But be careful! The game ends the moment you miss an apple, resetting your score to zero. It&amp;rsquo;s a delightful test of focus and a perfect way to take a quick break.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World in Many Languages</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/001-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/001-hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-global-greeting-card">&lt;strong>A Global Greeting Card&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3> &lt;p>This project is a simple yet elegant demonstration of one of the most fundamental concepts in programming and global communication: &amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;rdquo;. Generated with the help of Gemini, this webpage presents the iconic greeting in a diverse array of world languages, from Spanish to Hindi to Japanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each greeting is displayed on its own clean, well-defined card, making for a pleasant and easy-to-read layout. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic visual representation of how the same simple idea can be expressed across different cultures and scripts. The project serves as a perfect starting point for exploring web typography and internationalization (i18n).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interactive Self-Learning Robot</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/003-self-learning-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/003-self-learning-robot/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-glimpse-into-machine-learning">&lt;strong>A Glimpse into Machine Learning&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3> &lt;p>This fascinating project provides an interactive window into the world of artificial intelligence, specifically &lt;strong>reinforcement learning&lt;/strong>. You are presented with a simple car (our &amp;ldquo;robot&amp;rdquo;) on a track. Its goal? To learn how to navigate the track on its own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By clicking &amp;ldquo;Train&amp;rdquo;, you can watch as the robot begins its learning process through trial and error. It explores the environment, occasionally making mistakes, but gradually building a &amp;ldquo;brain&amp;rdquo; or a policy that guides it toward successful navigation. Once trained, you can &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo; its knowledge and watch it drive flawlessly. The simulation even allows you to save this learned model, demonstrating the concept of persisting a trained AI. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful, visual demonstration of how a machine can learn from experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>