<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software-Engineering on Gopi Palaniappan</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/tags/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Software-Engineering on Gopi Palaniappan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://gopipm.github.io/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Journey in Generative Code: From Pascal to Modern AI</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/generative-code-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/generative-code-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 10th grade, I wrote a Pascal program that could generate the source code for another executable program. What fascinated me was that one program could produce another that could run independently. Hence, &amp;ldquo;Generating Code.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went on to develop a Computer Graphics program for my final project where I would move the cursor on screen and place geometric shapes, record the coordinates and shape types in a data structure, and use that as input to &amp;ldquo;Generate code&amp;rdquo; that would independently execute and re-draw the original figure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Idea to MVP: A Technical Journey Building a Gen AI App</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/technicaljourneybuildingagenaiapp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/technicaljourneybuildingagenaiapp/</guid><description>&lt;p>A software engineer&amp;rsquo;s logbook on the iterative process of creating a feature-rich web application with a Large Language Model, highlighting the key lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-genesis-of-an-idea-">The Genesis of an Idea 💡&lt;/h2> &lt;p>Every software project begins with an idea. Mine was a desire to create a learning tool inspired by the teaching methods of Peter Norvig and Sebastian Thrun. I wanted a simple app that would present a new puzzle at the click of a button, but with a twist: it would also provide a detailed solution, explaining the nuances from a naive approach to an optimized one. The goal was to help users recognize underlying algorithmic patterns and improve their problem-solving skills.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>