<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Gopi Palaniappan</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Gopi Palaniappan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://gopipm.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Developer's Guide to the Exploding World of Gen AI Code Generators</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/a-developers-guide-to-gen-ai-code-generators/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/a-developers-guide-to-gen-ai-code-generators/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="navigating-the-ai-coding-revolution">Navigating the AI Coding Revolution&lt;/h2> &lt;p>Every week, it seems a new AI-powered coding tool enters the scene, promising to revolutionize our development workflows. As a developer constantly looking to optimize my process, I&amp;rsquo;ve been diving headfirst into this rapidly evolving ecosystem. From IDE extensions to standalone CLIs, the options are vast and varied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is my attempt to catalog and compare the various tools I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with recently. Many of these tools act as sophisticated frontends, connecting to powerful large language models (LLMs) like those from OpenAI, Google, or Anthropic, while others offer a more integrated, unique experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Journey in Generative Code: From Pascal to Modern AI</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/generative-code-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/generative-code-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 10th grade, I wrote a Pascal program that could generate the source code for another executable program. What fascinated me was that one program could produce another that could run independently. Hence, &amp;ldquo;Generating Code.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went on to develop a Computer Graphics program for my final project where I would move the cursor on screen and place geometric shapes, record the coordinates and shape types in a data structure, and use that as input to &amp;ldquo;Generate code&amp;rdquo; that would independently execute and re-draw the original figure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attempting to Clone a Genetic Algorithm Car Simulation: A Tale of Python, AI, and JavaScript</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/converting-python-car-sim-to-html-js/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/converting-python-car-sim-to-html-js/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-ambitious-goal-from-python-to-the-browser">The Ambitious Goal: From Python to the Browser&lt;/h2> &lt;p>As a fun side project, I recently became fascinated with a car simulation that used a genetic algorithm to teach virtual cars how to navigate a track. The original implementation, which you can find on &lt;a href="https://github.com/giaco91/Car-Race---An-evolutionary-Game.git" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a> , was written in Python, and I thought it would be a fantastic challenge to clone it for the web using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. My plan was to leverage AI coding assistants to help with the heavy lifting of translating the Python logic into a functional browser-based experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating My Blog: Using Gemini to Generate Hugo Posts</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/hugo-blog-post-creator-gems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/hugo-blog-post-creator-gems/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-quest-for-an-automated-ghost-writer">The Quest for an Automated Ghost Writer&lt;/h2> &lt;p>As a Technical Program Manager at Google with a deep passion for technology that stretches back to my first ZX Spectrum, I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for ways to blend my professional skills with my personal projects. My latest endeavor? Automating my Hugo-based blog. The ultimate goal is to create a fully autonomous &amp;ldquo;ghost writer&amp;rdquo; that can generate and publish content regularly. The first major step in this journey has been successfully setting up a workflow using Gemini to generate complete, formatted blog posts, just like this one!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breaking Stereotypes: From Play-Doh to Program Management</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/breaking-stereotypes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/breaking-stereotypes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Play-Doh is a great way for creative play and sensory exploration, allowing children to develop fine motor skills and express their imagination through molding, shaping, and manipulating the dough. Most people imagine play dough for sculpting and creating shapes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But did you know that you can use them as electrical conductors and use them to prototype parts and simple circuits for your hobby project? By mixing salt into the dough, it becomes conductive and can be used to create simple circuits and electronic devices. This unconventional use of play dough challenges stereotypes by demonstrating that everyday materials can have practical applications beyond their intended use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effortless Setup: Get Started with the Gemini CLI in Minutes</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/geminicli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/geminicli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting started with new command-line tools can sometimes feel like a chore, but I was pleasantly surprised by how simple it was to set up the Gemini CLI. As an AI-powered assistant that runs directly in your terminal, it&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer for developers, and the setup process is just as streamlined. This post will walk you through the quick installation and initial configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2> &lt;p>Before you start, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have &lt;strong>Node.js&lt;/strong> installed on your system. The Gemini CLI requires version 18 or higher. You can verify your version by running &lt;code>node -v&lt;/code> in your terminal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Embracing Curiosity: My Lifelong Journey of Learning to Learn</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/embracing-curiosity-learning-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/embracing-curiosity-learning-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Picture this: it’s the 1980s, I’m in 8th grade, and my dad brings home a shiny new ZX Spectrum.
For the uninitiated, this was the Atari of its day, loading games from cassette tapes that
screeched like a digital banshee while colorful lines danced across the screen. I was hooked,
playing Jet Set Willy and Dynamite Dan, but the real magic happened when I borrowed BASIC
programming books from the British Council Library in Bangalore. I dove into ASCII art through
bit manipulation and geeked out over POKE and PEEK commands, poking straight into the
machine’s memory to make graphics pop. That curiosity to tinker with a computer’s soul set the
stage for a lifelong love affair with learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World in Many Languages</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/000-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/000-hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="a-global-greeting-card">&lt;strong>A Global Greeting Card&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3> &lt;p>This project is a simple yet elegant demonstration of one of the most fundamental concepts in programming and global communication: &amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;rdquo;. Generated with the help of Gemini, this webpage presents the iconic greeting in a diverse array of world languages, from Spanish to Hindi to Japanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each greeting is displayed on its own clean, well-defined card, making for a pleasant and easy-to-read layout. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic visual representation of how the same simple idea can be expressed across different cultures and scripts. The project serves as a perfect starting point for exploring web typography and internationalization (i18n).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My First Crush: Effortless Multi-Model AI in the Terminal</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/coding-with-crush/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/coding-with-crush/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent some time today setting up and playing with a new tool, and I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely impressed. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href="https://github.com/charmbracelet/crush" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crush&lt;/a> , a new command-line interface for interacting with large language models from the brilliant minds at Charm Bracelet. The experience was so smooth that I had to write about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-beautiful-interface-for-all-the-models">A Beautiful Interface for All the Models&lt;/h2> &lt;p>The first thing that strikes you about &lt;code>crush&lt;/code> is its beautiful, intuitive interface. It lives in your terminal but feels incredibly modern and responsive. Getting started was a breeze. I already had a Gemini API key, so I plugged that in to get access to &lt;strong>Gemini 2.5 Pro&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stay Curious: The Timeless Power of Asking Questions</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/the-power-of-asking-questions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/the-power-of-asking-questions/</guid><description>&lt;p>As kids, we were encouraged to be curious and ask a lot of questions. That&amp;rsquo;s how we learned.
Maybe that motivates me to reach out to peers for help or ask for guidance without any inhibitions.
In college, as a back bencher it was fun to ask our teachers questions so they would pause and think themselves for an answer.
At work, as an engineer I asked a lot of questions to navigate complexity, troubleshoot a customer issue.
As a leader, we ask questions to help make decisions, gauge your team engagement and continuously learn from your team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The TPM's Two Pillars: Patience and Humility</title><link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/patience-and-humility-in-tpm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/patience-and-humility-in-tpm/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Technical Program Manager, patience and humility are critical traits that can help you succeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patience enables you to stay calm and make informed decisions even when faced with unpredictable or stressful situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Humility helps you build strong relationships with stakeholders and avoid becoming too attached to your own ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These two qualities are also closely related, as being humble can make you more patient and open-minded. By cultivating patience and humility, you can become a more effective leader and manage complex projects more successfully.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>