<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Gopi Palaniappan</title>
    <link>https://gopipm.github.io/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Gopi Palaniappan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://gopipm.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attempting to Clone a Genetic Algorithm Car Simulation: A Tale of Python, AI, and JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/converting-python-car-sim-to-html-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gopipm.github.io/blog/converting-python-car-sim-to-html-js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ambitious-goal-from-python-to-the-browser&#34;&gt;The Ambitious Goal: From Python to the Browser&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a fun side project, I recently became fascinated with a car simulation that used a genetic algorithm to teach virtual cars how to navigate a track. The original implementation, which you can find on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/giaco91/Car-Race---An-evolutionary-Game.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; , was written in Python, and I thought it would be a fantastic challenge to clone it for the web using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. My plan was to leverage AI coding assistants to help with the heavy lifting of translating the Python logic into a functional browser-based experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classic Apple Catch Game</title>
      <link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/002-apple-catch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/002-apple-catch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-fun-fast-paced-arcade-game&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Fun, Fast-Paced Arcade Game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Get ready for some classic arcade fun with &amp;ldquo;Apple Catch&amp;rdquo;! This charming game challenges your reflexes with a simple, addictive goal: move the basket at the bottom of the screen to catch the red apples as they fall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The controls are intuitive – just move your mouse left and right to guide the basket. Each apple you successfully catch adds to your score, which is proudly displayed in the top-left corner. But be careful! The game ends the moment you miss an apple, resetting your score to zero. It&amp;rsquo;s a delightful test of focus and a perfect way to take a quick break.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Self-Learning Robot</title>
      <link>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/003-self-learning-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gopipm.github.io/projects/003-self-learning-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-glimpse-into-machine-learning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Glimpse into Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This fascinating project provides an interactive window into the world of artificial intelligence, specifically &lt;strong&gt;reinforcement learning&lt;/strong&gt;. You are presented with a simple car (our &amp;ldquo;robot&amp;rdquo;) on a track. Its goal? To learn how to navigate the track on its own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By clicking &amp;ldquo;Train&amp;rdquo;, you can watch as the robot begins its learning process through trial and error. It explores the environment, occasionally making mistakes, but gradually building a &amp;ldquo;brain&amp;rdquo; or a policy that guides it toward successful navigation. Once trained, you can &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo; its knowledge and watch it drive flawlessly. The simulation even allows you to save this learned model, demonstrating the concept of persisting a trained AI. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful, visual demonstration of how a machine can learn from experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
